# **Benjamin Banwart**

Fort Scott, Kansas

Benjibanwart@gmail.com | (620)404-2094 | LinkedIn | GitHub | Portfolio Site

#### **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

Software Engineer with experience in full-stack web development including front-end, back-end, and testing. Currently attending a software engineering boot camp with KSU. Most efficient when working and collaborating with others. Avid lifetime learner and passionate about exceptional visual design and functionality.

#### **EDUCATION**

# **Kansas State University**

Manhattan, KS

Software Development Professional Certificate

Graduate in July of 2022

**Courses:** Front-End Development, UI-UX, Back-End Development and APIs, React-Redux, SQL and Data Modeling, MERN-stack Project, Principles of Programming in Python, Advanced Programming Topics

#### **SKILLS PROFILE**

**Certification:** Software Engineer

**Development Technologies:** JavaScript, TypeScript, Python, Flask, CSS, SASS, SCSS, HTML, AWS, GitHub, PgAdmin, C#, PSQL, Sequelize, APIs, Jinja, Git, React, Redux, NodeJS, Express, Bootstrap Material-UI, Mongoose,

Axios, macOS, Linux Databases: MongoDB, PostgreSQL

Deployment Tools: GitHub Pages, Heroku, Netlify, ElephantSQL, MongoDB Atlas, Amazon S3 Bucket, AWS Elastic

Beanstalk

#### PROJECT EXPERIENCE

**REST-Rant** March 2022

- Created a full-stack application that allows users to review restaurants.
- The app is hosted on Heroku and uses MongoDB as a database.
- Development technologies include JavaScript, Bootstrap, MongoDB, Express, NodeJS, JSX, and express-react-views.

MERNstagram May 2022

- Created a PERN-stack application in collaboration with three other classmates for a group milestone project.
- Create, view, edit, and delete social media posts with this application.
- The app is hosted in three places: the client is hosted on Netlify, the server is hosted on Heroku, and the Database is hosted with ElephantSQL.
- Development technologies include JavaScript, Material-UI, PostgreSQL, React, Git, ElephantSQL, PgAdmin, Axios, Express, NodeJS, and JSX.
- This project was instrumental in showing all of my group and I how to function as a team and properly use all of the different version control features of git.

Music API April 2022

- Created a JavaScript API for a music tour.
- Users can send requests, use all CRUD operations, and view responses rendered as JSON in the browser.
- Demonstrates a relational database with many tables.

API uses PostgreSQL as a database and implements Sequelize as an ODM.

## **NASA API Image Implementation**

February 2022 • Created a web page that

utilizes the NASA APOD API, JavaScript, and minimalist CSS styling.

• The page updates daily with a new image of space and a description of said image along with the title, author, and copyrights.

## Pokemon\_Battle\_Game

January 2022–February 2022

- Created a fully-functional browser Pokémon battle game using raw HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
- The JavaScript logic allows for a user to choose his or her party of Pokémon and then battle against a computer player until the user wins or loses.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

### **Hairbow Center, Fort Scott, KS**

February 2020–Present

Catalog Listing Assistant

- List highly detailed and niche products on Amazon, Etsy, Walmart
- Communicate regularly with the product analyst and the sales department in creating the varying products with details that are oriented for sales optimization

### Hairbow Center, Fort Scott, KS

April 2014-February 2020

Warehouse Laborer

- Worked in product production and conversion
- Converted large product units to multiple smaller product units while operating a machine
- Kept shelves saturated with products for pickers
- Troubleshot inventory errors using an online SKU-based inventory management system and communication with co-workers